chatroll.com 2019-05-13

# Chatroll — Privacy Policy

**This Privacy Policy was updated and is effective on June 24, 2018.**

The chatroll.com website (the "Website") is operated by Arithum Technologies Inc. carrying on business as Chatroll ("us", "we", "our", "the Company" or "Chatroll"). This privacy statement ("Privacy Policy") applies to the Website, and all associated services provided in connection with the Website that are owned and operated by Chatroll (collectively, "Service" or "Services"). 

We take privacy matters very seriously and we are committed to protect your privacy. 

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data. We use your data to provide and improve the Service. 

By visiting, submitting information to, or using any of our Services, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and accept our Terms of Service Agreement accessible at: <https://chatroll.com/legal>

Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service Agreement. 

### Definitions

#### Personal Data

Personal Data means any data relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from those data. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data.) 

#### Usage Data

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit.) 

#### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device.) 

#### Data Controller

Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed. 

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data. 

#### Data Processors (or Service Providers)

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

#### Data Subject (or User)

Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

### No User Under Age 18

Chatroll does not allow any anyone under the age of 18 to use our Service. **If you are under 18, please leave the site immediately.**

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us so we can take steps to remove their information from our servers. 

### Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you. The following Types of Data are collected: 

#### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to: 

  * Email address
  * Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

#### User Content

As part of your user profile, you may choose to submit profile information such as a description and photos. In addition to your profile information, we collect and archive all user materials that you post, including, but not limited to, chat messages. 

Your profile information and posted materials, with the exception of your profile email address, will be published via the Service unless stated otherwise. 

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information about how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data. 

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

Cookies are small pieces of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service. 

Cookies are a widely used and common internet technology. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, certain features of the Service may not function properly. 

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * **Session Cookies** : We use Session Cookies to identify and quickly retrieve login information to operate our Service.
  * **Analytics Cookies** : We use Analytics Cookies to analyze our Service, and to improve the functionality of our Service.

### Use of Data

Chatroll uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

### Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), Chatroll's legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it. 

Chatroll may process your Personal Data because:

  * We need to perform a contract with you
  * You have given us permission to do so
  * The processing is in our legitimate interests and it's not overridden by your rights
  * For payment processing purposes
  * To comply with the law

### Retention of Data

Chatroll will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies. 

Chatroll will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods. 

### Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. 

If you are located outside Canada and choose to provide information to us, please note that your data, including Personal Data, will be transferred to and processed in Canada and the United States. 

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer. 

Chatroll will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information. 

### Disclosure of Data

#### Business Transaction

If Chatroll is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy. 

#### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Chatroll may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency.) 

#### Legal Requirements

Chatroll may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: 

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Chatroll
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

#### User Assistance

We reserve the right to publish any request or feedback that you submit through email or other feedback mechanisms, in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. 

### Security of Data

We are committed to protecting your privacy and we take measures to ensure the privacy of your Personal Data. 

However, please be aware that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure or impenetrable. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

### "Do Not Track" Signals Under California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA)

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

### Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Chatroll aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data. 

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us. 

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights: 

  * **The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.** Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you. 

  * **The right of rectification.** You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.

  * **The right to object.** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.

  * **The right of restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.

  * **The right to data portability.** You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.

  * **The right to withdraw consent.** You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Chatroll relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

### Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. 

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. 

### Payments

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information. 

We work with Braintree, a PayPal service, as our payment processor. Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at: <https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>

### Third Parties

This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, or to individuals that we do not employ or manage. 

Our Service may contain links to other websites, and other websites may contain links to our Services. These other websites are not under our control. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. The privacy and security practices of websites linked to or from Chatroll are not covered by this Privacy Policy, and we are not responsible for the privacy or security practices or the content of such websites. 

We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. 

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to modify or update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page, and posting the date the Privacy Policy was last updated. 

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

Your continued use of the Service after any such change constitutes your acceptance of the new Policy. If you do not agree to the current or future conditions of the Policy, please do not continue to use or access the Service. It is your responsibility to regularly check the Policy to determine if there have been changes and to review such changes. 

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please email us at: **support@chatroll.com**
